Pablo Mansilla Ojeda

Software Engineer

pablo@ppamo.cl +56 9 8215 0949

Check my LinkedIn Page



I am a Software Engineer, with more than 20 years of experience and solid knowledge in software development in the banking, retail, and technology industry in companies such as IBM, Yapo, and Walmart.

I have high competencies in the development of services orchestrated over different platforms based on Kubernetes.

I possess effective and facilitating leadership integrating collaborative work and achievement of objectives, assertive problem resolution, change management, continuous training, productivity, and continuous improvement.

Education

Advanced Red Team Diploma

University of Santiago, Chile, 2023 - In progress

Red Team Diploma

University of Santiago, Chile, 2022

Master's in Technological Innovation

UTFSM, Chile, 2013

Computer Engineering

Austral University, Chile, 2003

Visual Arts Extension Diploma

University of Chile, 2020

Silicon Valley Immersion

University of San Francisco, California, 2013

IT Project Management Workshop

UTFSM, Chile, 2010

Diploma in Experimental Photographic Creation

University of Chile, 2009

Skills

Goal-Oriented
Facilitative Leadership
Change Management
Continuous Learning
Critical Thinking
Problem Solving

Work Experience

Walmart Chile - Retail External Software Engineer

June 2022 - March 2023

- We developed a service that enables the calculation of the total value of a shopping cart, deployed in Walmart's Cloud, and which consumes third-party services.
- For the solution, we created services written following the software product model designed by Walmart Chile, which aimed to ensure that deployed parts met a standard of observability and resilience.
- The work also involved integration with various technologies deployed in Azure.

Main Achievements

• We completed the development of a platform that allows the calculation of the total amount to be paid online.

Tags: Kubernetes, WCNP, Golang, NodeJS, Microsoft SQL Server, Redis, Kafka

IBM Chile - Technology

Software Engineer

November 2017 - February 2022

- I participate in multiple projects, each one being executed at different clients, many of them banks.
- All projects were developed for the Cloud, and shared a similar architecture starting with a web or mobile client that consumed APIs which composed or aggregated the results of different microservices.
- Additionally, I managed servers and clusters in client dependencies, performing volumetric analysis of the services and performance adjustments to the servers and services.
- I designed and implemented workflows for the team and tools to automate some of these tasks.

Main Achievements

• I received the "IBM Excellence Award" for my participation in a high visibility project for the company, and a technical recognition for my work in the development and integration of services using OpenShift...

Tags: Kubernetes, IBM Api Connect, Gitlab, Golang, Node, Openshift, Cloudant, RHEL

Corporación de Desarrollo Tecnológico Bienes de Capital - Innovation

Technological Innovation Project Evaluator

March 2015 - December 2016

• I perform the technical evaluation of projects that participate in various CORFO innovation contests, rating their technical, financial, and commercial merit, to determine their viability and adherence to the contest rules.

Schibsted Chile - Marketplace

Software Engineer

August 2013 - December 2016

• I worked on the development and integration of new features on the site and improvements in internal development processes with multidisciplinary and self-managed teams following some aspects of Scrum.

Main Achievements

• I coordinated the design of the team's workflow and its integration with other areas of the organisation. In addition, we completed the integration of an API developed by a team from another country with our backend, within a limited time frame, and that due to company commitments did not allow for delays or errors.

Tags: Linux, Postgres, PHP, Python, NodeJs, Golang, C, Redis, RabbitMQ, Git, Jenkins, Selenium, Docker

Bell Technologies - Technology

External Software Engineer

April 2010 - May 2013

- I worked as an External Engineer, executing software development projects and improving development processes in different departments.
- Most of the projects involved creating data providers to connect the self-service machine interface with client services.

Tags: Visual Studio .Net, Team Foundation Services, IVR, Linux, ATM

Mercatus Chile - Technology

Software Engineer

April 2004 - April 2012

April 2004 - April 2012

- I served as a software developer and systems administrator in a Linux environment, working with the .Net Framework.
- Later the company was acquired by a Norwegian Microsoft Golden Partner, which led us to migrate all our servers to Microsoft technology.

Tags: Visual Studio .Net, Microsoft SQL Server, Linux, Microsoft, Virtualization, Continuous Integration

Universidad Austral de Chile - Education

Teacher

• In the 'Technological Research Seminar' course of the Computing Engineering program at the Puerto Montt Campus of the Austral University, I conduct research in the field of robotics. We created our own robot using PC parts and worked in a Linux environment, where we designed an open architecture, developed applications to control the robot, and drivers to manage the hardware components.

Tags: Linux, PcBot, Mono, Monobotics, Robot, Hardware, Drivers